<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://www.adrianparker.com/">
  <title>AdrianParker.com</title>
  <subtitle>Writing by Adrian Parker, on topics like product management, finance, software, investment, and travel; adorned with whimsical anecdotes about life.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://www.adrianparker.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2024-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://www.adrianparker.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Adrian Parker</name>
    <email>adrian@iceknife.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>My Favourite Part of My Last Vacation</title>
    <link href="https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Favourite-Part-Of-Last-Vacation/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Favourite-Part-Of-Last-Vacation/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What was your favorite part of your last vacation?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite part of my last vacation &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Favourite-Part-Of-Last-Vacation/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; was going on a diving trip to the Mercury Islands, off the coast of Whitianga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just because they were two great dives - best I&#39;ve had in New Zealand by far, with masses of demoiselle&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Favourite-Part-Of-Last-Vacation/#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, moray eels, a crayfish, a great buddy, funny and friendly crew, and interesting sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason this day was my favourite is because I went on a dive trip with people I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, the other three snorkelled, while I dived, but that didn&#39;t matter at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was seeing them happy, being happy with them, and having us all together, out there on the boat, in the real world, doing this adventurous thing, doing something I love to do, in a far flung spot, with other people who also love those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the togetherness that made it special, combined with the activity itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out on the water is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out on the water with my loved ones is fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post was my response to Week #4 of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://randsprompts.substack.com/p/rands-writing-prompts-4-february&quot;&gt;Rands Writing Prompts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Favourite-Part-Of-Last-Vacation/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;First encounter with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Zealand_demoiselle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;demoiselle&lt;/a&gt;. Similar to blue mao mao, but have two prominent white dots. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Favourite-Part-Of-Last-Vacation/#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to make a Wine Cork Notice Board</title>
    <link href="https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Wine-Cork-Notice-Board-How-To/"/>
    <updated>2023-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Wine-Cork-Notice-Board-How-To/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;How to make a Wine Cork Notice Board&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not generally regarded as an arts and crafts type of person. Arts, perhaps, especially the musical kind; and crafty, sure, I can identify with that; but put the two words together and generally thats&#39;s enough to make me run for the hills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However I&#39;ve been collecting wine corks for seemingly forever, and the last couple of years I&#39;ve been assiduously putting off this project, until last weekend when I said to myself, you know what, get it done. And so I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m amazed it turned out so well, so the least I could do is share with you how easy it is to do for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What you will need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any good online tutorial, we begin with the ingredients. You will need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A large, blank photo frame - mine has a frame internal area of 3500 cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of glue - I used spray on but paste will work fine I guess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Stanley knife (AKA box cutter, or utility knife)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small person - but not so small they can&#39;t be trusted with a Stanley knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 1 cork per 9 cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of frame internal area
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can use both halves of the corks if your corks are interesting on both sides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if so, you can go with 1 cork per 18 cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of frame internal area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a handful of extra corks as well, to allow for bad cuts and breakages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/FSeGrtF8kb-400.webp 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/FSeGrtF8kb-800.webp 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/FSeGrtF8kb-400.jpeg 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/FSeGrtF8kb-800.jpeg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/FSeGrtF8kb-800.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Components of the new wine cork notice board pre-assembly&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Components of the new wine cork notice board pre-assembly&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit your small person down with the Stanley knife and the corks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instruct small person to cut the corks length ways, preserving the most interesting details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting corks is easier if you cut multiple times...
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cut the whole length each time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only cut a a third of the depth each time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;three shallow cuts is much easier that one full depth cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set to one side any offcuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the frame has glass, take that out so you just have the backing board and the frame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test any features you plan to have, like champagne corks in the corners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glue in the feature pieces in the desired locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spray an area on the backing board about as big as your hand, then fill it with the feature
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be generous with your glue!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check you have enough corks to fill the left over space in the frame
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are aiming to fill horizontally edge to edge in the gaps between the feature pieces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to fill all the gaps, using offcuts cut to shape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting top left, glue in the remaining corks length ways with interesting text facing outwards
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aiming to fill the frame top to bottom left to right with straight corks when possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glue offcuts in the small gaps that inevitable appear until there are no gaps left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/AWOI4CxR_I-400.webp 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/AWOI4CxR_I-800.webp 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/AWOI4CxR_I-400.jpeg 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/AWOI4CxR_I-800.jpeg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/AWOI4CxR_I-800.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The finished wine cork notice board&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The finished wine cork notice board&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK all that is left to do now is install it on your wall. You may also like to pay your small person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a stud finder to find a suitably strong part of the wall, then measure carefully to get the notice board square and level in your space.
Hang it, and enjoy the tranquility of being able to pin random bits of paper on the wall!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/UZ_0u8P2VE-400.webp 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/UZ_0u8P2VE-800.webp 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/UZ_0u8P2VE-400.jpeg 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/UZ_0u8P2VE-800.jpeg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/UZ_0u8P2VE-800.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Installed wine cork notice board above a bench, where random bits of paper tend to collect&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Installed wine cork notice board above a bench, where random bits of paper tend to collect&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You&#39;re Already Not Dating Her</title>
    <link href="https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Already-Not-Dating-Her/"/>
    <updated>2023-07-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Already-Not-Dating-Her/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The Wisdom of Dave Navarro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be familiar already with the music of Jane&#39;s Addiction. I discovered them early in my love affair with rock music. Fronted by enigmatic singer Perry Farrell, featuring the creative percussion of Stephen Perkins, the spacious, melodic bass of Eric Avery, and soaring above it all, the epic guitar stylings of Dave Navarro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Navarro isn&#39;t just an intensely gifted musician though. He is so much more. Not least, a philosopher of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dabbling in Dark Matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you knew already that Dave Navarro is a renowned American guitarist known for his groundbreaking work with rock band Jane&#39;s Addiction and collaborations with other bands like Red Hot Chili Peppers. His innovative, searing guitar style and genre-blending approach have left an indelible mark on the music industry. Beyond music, Navarro has dabbled in television hosting, acting, and directing, solidifying his multifaceted career and ongoing influence. He sleeps in a coffin, swings suspended in mid air by his piercings, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laweekly.com/dave-navarro-made-me-cry/&quot;&gt;makes journalists cry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you may not have discovered yet though is his endlessly entertaining radio show &amp;quot;Dark Matter&amp;quot;, that aired primarily in the mid 2000s on community radio in the USA. Generally clocking in around two hours long, Dark Matter was a captivating radio show hosted by Dave Navarro with co-hosts Todd Newman, Dan Cleary, Jessica Sattelberger and Engineer Frank, that delved into the realms of the unknown, exploring topics like conspiracy theories, paranormal phenomena, and the mysteries of the universe. A typical show consisted of some music, a lot of in jokes, the occasional guest interview, some Los Angeles gossip, and frequently, live calls into the show from the listening public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;best&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; parts were the live calls in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You&#39;re On The Air&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a popular musician, particularly one who plays in an angsty emotional hard rock band, means you attract a certain type of fan. Generally the callers in to Dark Matter were male, teenage or in their twenties, not so educated, not necessarily all that happy with their lot. Usually they&#39;d ask about music, Dave&#39;s bands, other bands; and frequently they would be mocked mercilessly by the hosts. The next most common questions though were about one universal topic. Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Navarro has a certain sex appeal, if you like that kind of thing; and his rock star pedigree combined with an enthusiasm for adult entertainment and an infamous marriage to Carmen Electra, herself a sex symbol of some note, all seemed to add up to Dave being seen by his fan base as a man who knows about love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical call about affairs of the heart would go along these lines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Dave, there&#39;s a girl that I like but she&#39;s a ten and I&#39;m a four and I&#39;m too scared to tell her how I feel.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The co-hosts would tease the caller a little at this point, pointing out six points is likely a bridge too far, and maybe it&#39;d help if the guy showered every now and then; but after a moment Dave would cut in and say something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Just ask her out already.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To which the caller would respond, and this might start to ring a bell with you too, just a little, indirectly...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;But what if she says no?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is where the wisdom came in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You&#39;re Already Not F**king Her&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave would invariably reply &amp;quot;Dude! It doesn&#39;t matter what she says. &lt;strong&gt;You&#39;re already not f**king her&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this bombshell had landed, he&#39;d explain it out just to make sure everyone understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You&#39;re already not dating her right? She doesn&#39;t know you exist? So ask her out! The worst that happens is... nothing changes! She&#39;s not dating you now, and, if she says no, she&#39;s still not dating you. You&#39;ve got nothing to lose.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s good advice. Wisdom for life. I don&#39;t recall if anyone ever called back into Dark Matter weeks later to announce they were now neck deep in a rewarding relationship with the new girl of their dreams, I like to think they did. But that&#39;s not the real teaching Dave gives us. The real wisdom he imparts has nothing to do with girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Dave is really teaching us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Navarro is really teaching us that a positive possible outcome, untested, has no more value to us than that same possibility, tested, that failed. It is rare that trying and failing leaves us in a worse place than not trying at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grasping this universal equation gives us power to try. We have to dare to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nothing changes by inaction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&#39;t have the outcome we desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we don&#39;t try to get the outcome, we keep not having the outcome. Nothing changes through inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we do try to get the outcome, but we fail, we keep not having the outcome. Nothiing changes through faiilure. (Except, more than likely, we move on to desiring a new outcome we may be able to succeed with)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sense of loss we experience, that we might not get the outcome we want if we but try, is generally &lt;em&gt;not rational&lt;/em&gt; - we won&#39;t get that outcome if we &lt;em&gt;don&#39;t try&lt;/em&gt;, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only way to get the outcome is to try.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All we might lose, generally, is the possibility. But possibilities are like sunrises. There&#39;s always another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Omission Bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another term for Dave&#39;s timeless wisdom is &amp;quot;omission bias&amp;quot;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thedecisionlab.com/biases/omission-bias&quot;&gt;Omission bias&lt;/a&gt; refers to our tendency to judge harmful actions as worse than harmful inactions, even if they result in similar consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We judge asking the girl out on a date as worse than never talking to her, even though both result in the same outcome - not pursuing our romantic aspirations. Action is worse than inaction, we tell ourselves, even though demonstrably that is not true. Indeed, you may consider inaction is worse as you continue to carry the mental baggage of an outcome desired but unachieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Applying the Wisdom of Dave in Everyday Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want the lead role in the school theatrical production? But if you audition, and you aren&#39;t chosen, the dream of being on that stage in the limelight will be crushed. The idea of it stings. You mentally push away from the discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go audition. You already don&#39;t have the role, and if you audition, worst case is, you still don&#39;t have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to buy a property, at auction, but you want it so much and it&#39;s perfect in every way and what if your bid is too low or someone outbids you and you don&#39;t end up owning it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You already don&#39;t live there. Go bid. There&#39;s nothing to lose, and there are other properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s your dream job, that next step up, but you don&#39;t have some of the laundry list of skills and experiences they&#39;re asking for, and what if it is beyond you? You might not get the job! Why apply?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put your application in. You already don&#39;t work there. If you don&#39;t get the job - you still don&#39;t work there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With practice, I have found you can apply this reasoning in many areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal life, professional life; often in both areas we limit ourselves from trying, out of an irrational sense we might lose the possibility of achieving the outcome we dream of, if we actually try to achieve it. Understand that possibilities are easily replaced, they don&#39;t have value of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the girl out. You&#39;re already not dating her. It&#39;s what Dave Navarro would do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cognitive Reframing</title>
    <link href="https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Cognitive-Reframing/"/>
    <updated>2023-05-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Cognitive-Reframing/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Small and lost and confused&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pulled up outside the flat. Mum made parking the car look harder than usual, she was preoccupied with something, anxious. Perhaps I was eight? There or thereabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt small and lost and confused. Something wasn&#39;t right with Mum, I wasn&#39;t in school, we were outside this strange place, struggling to parallel park, and all I really remember is feeling a long way out of place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t know that Mum was visiting the hospital.&lt;br /&gt;
Later, I knew, but not then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You didn&#39;t give kids context back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Biscuits in the kitchen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went inside. It was small, but welcoming, shafts of sunlight through the net curtains, piles everywhere, loved things, things of value. TV in the corner, maybe it was on during the day, it never would have been at our place. Fruit bowl on the table. A plate of home made biscuits. A pot of tea. It felt warm, friendly, homely; but it didn&#39;t feel like our home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lady greeted us. She lived there. Mum knew her, I didn&#39;t. She was shorter than Mum, and older, she talked a lot, in a kindly way, buzzing around like a bird hovering around a nest. There was a husband, she explained. And two boys. Murphy, and Harry. They were older than me, and not there, but I was a boy and they were boys and so I was deposited in the bedroom they shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room felt foreign. Clothes on the floor. A general sense of chaos. Sports equipment everywhere. I found a comic book, I remember feeling grateful, like finding a life raft after being abandoned at sea.
Mum and the lady closed the door to go talk in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an eternity but only an hour or two, having read every comic book I could find, I ventured down the hall. The lady was in the kitchen, buzzing around, chirping to herself, but Mum was gone. I don&#39;t remember what she said, exactly, Mum would be back, not to worry, or words to that effect. I felt small, and alone. She sat me down at the table, and gave me a biscuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A biscuit made things a little better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was my earliest memory of Elsa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Biscuits at the door&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a time, a year or two, I was left in Elsa&#39;s care fairly regularly. Mum had to go to the hospital a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doctors didn&#39;t know what it was, until they did. Multiple sclerosis. It took them a while though, it was new back then, and while they worked it out, I spent a lot of time eating Elsa&#39;s biscuits and re-reading comic books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Murphy once or twice, Elsa&#39;s son. He seemed nice, a bit older than me, as sporty as his room implied. Opposite to me in every respect. I don&#39;t know what he made of this  geeky kid that showed up every now and then. But he, just like his Mum, accepted me and treated me kindly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually though, multiple sclerosis changed the script. As it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mum went from visiting the hospital, to being visited at the hospital, where she now permanently stayed. The journey took a few years. And while she moved in one direction, my father and I moved in the other. Circumstances forced independence, I looked after myself, we both learned how to keep a home.&lt;br /&gt;
I didn&#39;t need to stay at Elsa&#39;s any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa wasn&#39;t the type to be discouraged though. Just like that hovering bird, she kept an eye on us fledglings that left the nest. She would call, on the old bakelite phone screwed to the kitchen wall, at random times out of the blue, and would chat, at length, with whoever answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa&#39;d update you on her family, who you didn&#39;t know, and the local goings on. She&#39;d ask after the folks she hadn&#39;t met, peppering the conversation with blessings and heartfelt proclamations of love. We&#39;d roll our eyes when we realised it was Elsa on the line, settling in for the long haul, but you&#39;d enjoy chatting all the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt normal. It stayed the same. Not a lot else did back then.&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes she&#39;d leave biscuits at the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Biscuits at the funerals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mum was in hospital a really long time. Elsa stopped bringing biscuits at some point, but she didn&#39;t stop calling, just every now and then, much to my father&#39;s delight. I&#39;d already left home.&lt;br /&gt;
Elsa didn&#39;t have my number. Dad took one for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually Mum died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw Elsa at the funeral. We hugged, we cried. I thanked her, she told me there was nothing to thank her for. Of course there was. From all of us there was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa kept calling Dad, just every now and then. Kept in touch. In touch with her extended family, their adventures, people we&#39;d never met. I met a girl, we got married, we moved overseas. We sent Christmas cards, with news filled letters, Elsa was on the list. I like to think it gave her something to talk about when she called my father, just every now and then. Not that she needed any help with conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually Dad died too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another funeral, more biscuits. Shortly thereafter, Elsa started calling my parents in law instead. They&#39;d met exactly once. A couple of years after that, we moved back home. We kept sending Christmas cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I decided to go visit Elsa. I don&#39;t recall why. Perhaps I had realised older folk like being visited. So I dropped around, unannounced, knocked on the door, and after just the shortest while waiting on the doorstep wondering if anyone was home, the door inched open, and there Elsa was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Biscuits from the packet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa was smaller than I remembered, frailer, a proper little old lady now. But the sparkle was still in her eyes! She buzzed around, fluttered her wings, dragged me inside. It was small, but welcoming, shafts of sunlight through the net curtains, piles everywhere, loved things, things of value. TV in the corner, on during the day. Just the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa made tea. We sat at the kitchen table, and talked. She served biscuits from a packet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was ten years ago. Elsa got my number. My parents-in-law seemed relieved. Every now and then she&#39;d call. Sometimes I&#39;d visit. Sometimes I&#39;d take the kids. She&#39;d buzz and hover and feed them biscuits. The light in her eyes never went out, but the conversation got more erratic as time marched on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One visit Murphy was there and Elsa carried on like we were the oldest of friends finally reunited. We barely remembered each other. We had nothing common, other than that moment, and our unspoken agreement to smile and let Elsa reunite us the way she clearly needed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another visit Elsa sat me down in the kitchen, rummaged about in the cupboard, and presented me with a photo frame. &amp;quot;That&#39;s you!&amp;quot; she exclaimed. &amp;quot;Remember? You were so young! So handsome!&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
I assured Elsa it was just like yesterday. I let her press the photo into my arms when I left.&lt;br /&gt;
I didn&#39;t recognise the kid at all. It wasn&#39;t me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not long after that, or so it felt, Murphy messaged, Elsa had a fall, was in hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I visited. Smaller, frailer, fewer stories to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Biscuits my daughter made&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa went into care. I visited her there, took the kids, changed where we sent the Christmas cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa would still tell stories, from her childhood now, punctuated with &amp;quot;do you remember&amp;quot;s that I didn&#39;t, people I didn&#39;t know, memories that hadn&#39;t happened, at least not to me. We held her hand. Agreed with everything she said. Left a little sad. My daughter made biscuits. We ate them. Elsa didn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gradually visits became less common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A visit was long overdue. I&#39;d been putting it off, not made it a priority. I wrote &amp;quot;we&#39;ll come see you soon&amp;quot; in this year&#39;s Christmas card. I meant it. We were going overseas on a holiday in April. We&#39;d go after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just after I toggled off airplane mode at Singapore, Murphy&#39;s message arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsa had died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were out of the country for a few weeks. I missed the funeral, if there was one. No more Christmas cards. Elsa is now just a pleasant memory, one that reminds me of the power of showing up, and unbridled positivity. That&#39;s another blog post though. This one is about what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get to that, though, I want to introduce just a little bit of psychology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cognitive Reframing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognitive reframing is a powerful technique that involves changing the way we think about a situation, event, or problem in order to view it from a more positive or constructive perspective. It allows us to challenge negative or unhelpful thoughts and replace them with thoughts that are more beneficial and realistic. By reframing our thoughts, we can shift our mindset, improve our emotional well-being, and approach challenges with a more optimistic outlook, ultimately leading to personal growth and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use cognitive reframing frequently. Here are a couple of examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just started a new job, attended an online meeting, got a chance to add to the discussion. I thought I made my point well, but noticed two colleagues start laughing as I finished (thankfully, on mute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately I felt they must be laughing at me. Maybe it was what I had said? Maybe it was what I was wearing? I spent the rest of the meeting feeling foolish. An hour or so later, still feeling bad, I sat myself down and thought - I don&#39;t know why those colleagues started laughing, I never will. Maybe it was me, maybe not. I can choose to think it wasn&#39;t me, and that will be my reality, so I did, and then I felt better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more impactful example is how I felt after Elsa passed away. I don&#39;t mind admitting, once we were back from our travels, when I had time to sit and think, I felt really bad. What a terrible person I had been, I said to myself. I hadn&#39;t visited Elsa enough. I hadn&#39;t given her more of my time. I hadn&#39;t adopted her into our family. So many things I hadn&#39;t said or done. I hadn&#39;t reached amazing. I felt sad and regretful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are just thoughts though. Not facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It isn&#39;t the way it &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt;  be.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve learned when you have negative feelings, they come from your thoughts. If something comes from your thoughts, then you can use cognitive reframing, you can change those thoughts to something more positive. You might choose to think, &amp;quot;I am grateful for the time I did spend with them,&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I have so many good memories of the times we shared together.&amp;quot; By focusing on the positive aspects of the time I spent with Elsa, I can honour her memory and feel better about the time we had together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to use cognitive reframing is to challenge your negative thoughts. If you catch yourself thinking something negative, like &amp;quot;I didn&#39;t spend enough time with them,&amp;quot; you can challenge that thought. You can ask yourself, &amp;quot;Did I really waste the time I had with them?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;What are some positive memories I have of our time together?&amp;quot; This can help you see things more objectively and less negatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another technique I usd. I thought about the time I had given to Elsa. The things we &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; do. The caring we shared. The ways we did show up, for each other in turn, regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to frame my relationship with Elsa as one of a kid she helped many years ago, who stayed in touch throughout her life, and brought her a little light, in little ways, ways that meant something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I challenged my negative thoughts, and compared how I did show Elsa my gratitude and affection. I reminded myself of the times she told me her son Harry never called. And how I reassured her Harry of course always had her in his thoughts and would call when he could. (I lied, by the way, but nicely).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use cognitive reframing to put things into perspective.&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes, when we&#39;re feeling upset about something, we can blow it out of proportion. We might think we&#39;re the worst person in the world because we didn&#39;t spend enough time with our loved one. By putting things into perspective, we can see that the situation isn&#39;t as bad as we thought. Ultimately this too has helped me come to terms with Elsa&#39;s passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did what we could. There&#39;s no tragedy, no deficiency, no one has a score card that says I didn&#39;t pass the Elsa exam. I did what I did and it was better than if I hadn&#39;t done it. That&#39;s how I choose to frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I can offer some advice, dear reader, then I suggest you add cognitive reframing to your toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognitive reframing is a powerful tool that can help you feel better and more positive about yourself and your life. Remember to focus on the positive memories, challenge your negative thoughts, and put things into perspective. With practice, you&#39;ll find that cognitive reframing becomes easier and more natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, send old folks Christmas cards, visit when you can, and eat biscuits while you listen to their stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#39;t matter how many times you didn&#39;t do it. All that matters is how many times you did.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Generosity is a Customer Experience Superpower</title>
    <link href="https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Generosity-Customer-Experience-Superpower/"/>
    <updated>2023-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.adrianparker.com/posts/Generosity-Customer-Experience-Superpower/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;We cancelled your credit card&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email from my bank began nicely enough but went downhill quickly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;q&gt;We&#39;ve cancelled your credit card due to an unauthorised card not present transaction in Los Angeles&lt;/q&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not unreasonable, given I live 10,800 kilometres away and haven&#39;t visited LA in a decade. It definitely wasn&#39;t me trying a quick $10 spend at the local 7-11 and my bank rightfully knew it. I couldn&#39;t fault their reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unwelcome news though, given it meant both living within our cash reserves for a spell, and remembering to change the card details for all those things that end up charging us once every whenever. Netflix, life insurance, all the various subscriptions you managed to forget, well at least until the late payment notice comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in product, I should be grateful for the opportunity to review lots of different versions of the Update your Card Details feature, but... there are only so many times one needs reminding how woefully common poor form UX is. No, I don&#39;t live in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a pain I could have done without. Still, nothing to be done but grit one&#39;s teeth and get on with it. So I did. Thought I had changed them all, but then...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We noticed an error... and we&#39;re fixing it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It won&#39;t surprise regular readers of this blog (ha! who am I kidding? this is the very first post. If you&#39;re reading this, welcome! Please subscribe!) to learn some of our regular credit card payments are winery subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every so often, a winery you like so much that you trust them to not just dump  stock on you, sends you some bottles, they just arrive on your doorstep a day or two after your card is charged. When you find a winery whose style you really enjoy, it&#39;s a great way to stay connected without having to remember to shop, or make decisions about which wines to buy. Commerce that comes to you. It&#39;s a beautiful thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subscriptions come infrequently though, every 3 or 4 months, sometimes annually, and sure enough I didn&#39;t manage to update all of ours. One such forgotten update was our subscription at &lt;a href=&quot;https://astrolabewines.co.nz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Astrolabe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/external-link.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Opens in new tab&quot; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time had passed after the card cancellation, so much so I was beginning to think the annoyance was behind us for good, when another email arrived... &lt;q&gt;Your subscription payment has failed...&lt;/q&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once more into the breach I went. This particular email direct linked me to their website (nice), but that link dropped me at a new subscription sign up page. That didn&#39;t feel right, but, I poked around and could find no way to update my existing subscription, so I went ahead and entered my details again.&lt;br /&gt;No doubt you are smarter than me and can see where this is going, but, well, it gets better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later I got &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; &lt;q&gt;Payment failed&lt;/q&gt; email, and, not thinking much, I went and tried to update my card details &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;... and did the exact same, &lt;q&gt;guess I need a new subscription, hope it works this time&lt;/q&gt; all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;q&gt;Your payment failed&lt;/q&gt; emails stopped so I pushed that vague sense of unease it didn&#39;t feel quite right to one side and went about my day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all that much to my surprise, a few days later I received yet another email regarding our Astrolabe subscription. But this time it was from an actual person. Thankfully Tash had noticed we were about to be sent two shipments and rather than letting it just happen, they intercepted the delivery, looked at my account, worked out I didn&#39;t want two of the same thing at the same time, cancelled the second credit card charge, and then &lt;em&gt;emailed me to let me know they had both noticed the error and also fixed it&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the interaction had finished there, I would have been impressed enough by this attentive service to tell other people about it, but, although I didn&#39;t know it yet, Astrolabe were, in fact, just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Waghorns look forward to meeting you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replied to explain I had indeed made an error and thanked them for saving me a lot of hassle and more than a little bit of money by not honouring the subscriptions I had inadvertently signed myself up for. All of that went well, Tash was gracious and understanding, and towards the end of our conversation, Tash added to proceedings that if we were ever passing by Marlborough we should stop by the winery and have a tasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happened, we did have plans to be nearby a couple of months later on our summer holiday camping trip, so I mentioned if we could fit it into our plans, we would, and that was that. All very pleasant in the end, and what could have been a poor experience ended up being quite positive. Good customer service for the win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I recall, it was around New Year&#39;s Day, we were halfway into our camping trip, up to our ears in sunscreen and insect repellent, when I remembered this opportunity, had a good look in the calendar, and emailed Tash back, months later by that stage, asking if we could stop by the winery around 2pm on a particular day only a few days later. It felt pretty chance-y, we could only make that one slot work and it was very little notice. I steeled myself for the &lt;q&gt;sorry we&#39;re booked out&lt;/q&gt; response. But that&#39;s not what happened next. No, not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead the email I got back said the date and time were fine, and gave an address, and signed off &lt;q&gt;The Waghorns are looking forward to meeting you&lt;/q&gt;. I wasn&#39;t sure who the Waghorns were, to be honest, guess they run the cellar door? But didn&#39;t give it a lot of thought, after all our luck was in, they could do the specific time that worked for us, happy days! So we locked it in the schedule and got back to lazing about in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later came round way too fast. We tore down the campsite, wedged it all back in the car somehow, and drove a couple of hours, next stop the winery. We drove through the town I thought it would be in, then out the other side, then following the GPS like you do, we turned off the highway into a quiet country road, and went down there a bit, took a left, then a right, and eventually we arrived at a nondescript farm gate in the middle of seemingly nowhere. Pasture to the left, forest to the right, all very lovely but nothing that looked like a winery at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had that discussion about whether it was the GPS or my driving that was at fault, concluded likely it was both, but we checked the address and we did seem to be in the right place, so we explored down this private driveway some distance. Went past a place, it looked like a private home, went on some more, and ended up driving up a driveway of a very nice farmhouse. Huge country manor type of place. Big enough that it had a robot mowing the lawn. I knocked on the extra-large back door. Twice. No one answered, and the lawn mower didn&#39;t have anything useful to add, so we turned the car around and headed back down the drive, writing this one off to experience as we went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You&#39;re the Parkers, right?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we approached the gate, a young-ish man appeared, jogging towards us, and he seemed friendly enough,  gave us a friendly wave, so we paused. I prepared my best &lt;q&gt;so sorry if this is your place, we&#39;re lost, honest&lt;/q&gt; line, wound down the window, but before I could get started the gentleman leaned his head into the gap, gave us a big smile , and asked... &lt;q&gt;you&#39;re the Parkers, right?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were! Much to our delight, the charming young man was named Finn, and he was indeed from Astrolabe, which he explained was the place we&#39;d driven past after the gate. &lt;q&gt;But it just looks like a house&lt;/q&gt;, I said, but he assured us it was the right place, so we returned, parked under the tree, let the kids and the dogs run free and followed Finn around the back of what turned out to be, exactly what it looked like - their house. We&#39;d been invited to their place. Not the shop, not the commercial premises, not even the winery itself. Instead it was their home. Like we were friends, instead of random strangers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we met Arabella, one of the winemakers, and their family dog met ours, and before we could pinch ourselves to make sure we weren&#39;t dreaming, we met Simon, the chief winemaker, and we were following him through the vines taking in a masterclass in viticulture. We spent a good half an hour soaking up decades of experience and wisdom, and Simon was very gracious in putting up with our simple questions without ever making us feel silly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/1Z5LuOzU_e-400.webp 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/1Z5LuOzU_e-800.webp 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/1Z5LuOzU_e-400.jpeg 400w, https://www.adrianparker.com/img/1Z5LuOzU_e-800.jpeg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 400px, 800px&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adrianparker.com/img/1Z5LuOzU_e-800.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Wandering The Farm vineyard being taught about chardonnay by a master winemaker&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Wandering The Farm vineyard being taught about chardonnay by a master winemaker&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And then the chilly bin came out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was already a most unexpected treat for a keen wine enthusiast like me, it&#39;s not often you get the chance to talk at length about grapes in the vineyard with one of New Zealand&#39;s leading winemakers, but then one of the Waghorns asked if we wanted to get on and taste a couple? Did we what! We ended up sitting around a lovely table under a sun umbrella, our children found their way onto the family trampoline like they&#39;d been visiting every summer their whole lives, and then the chilly bin came out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent what must have been the best part of two hours tasting multiple examples and vintages of many varieties of Astrolabe wine. Handsome pours, experiments, older vintages and if I recall even an unreleased one or two, and paired with a wide ranging, few holds barred conversation about all things wine. We were enraptured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the chance to ask the questions we had always wanted to know, like how did they really see wine critics, and competitions, and scores, and what about the impacts of climate change? The differences between making for export and for home market, the economics and the realities of being a quality focussed producer versus being a big brand producer, their thoughts on succession in the company and much more besides. Through the course of the conversation Simon shared hilarious tales from his career that had us in stitches and Finn and I even shared notes on cooking pork slow on the barbecue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words don&#39;t really do the experience justice. The Waghorns were perfect hosts, completely accessible and beyond generous both with their products and their time. We couldn&#39;t believe how lucky we were to experience such hospitality. As conversation started to come to a natural conclusion, I was mentally working out how much wine we could possibly afford to buy as our way of thanking them and paying tribute  for their time and efforts. There was no shop, we were literally in their back yard, but I guessed they would perhaps introduce a price list and we&#39;d do what we could, within our limited means, to empty their shelves. But that moment never came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No quid pro quo expected&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, Simon asked us which our favourites had been, a harder question to answer than it sounds given how good the range is cross the board, but we managed it, and they rustled about a bit in the chilly bin and handed us two of the only slightly open bottles, and said - &lt;q&gt;you&#39;d better take those with you for dinner&lt;/q&gt;. They just gave them to us. Full stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond gobsmacked by this point, we did our best to maintain our composure, thanked them profusely, found our children and pets, got it all in the car and departed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we drove to our next accommodation (fear not dear reader, I was the designated driver and had played tasting very much on the safe side) it occurred to me that of course, a cellar door sale was never on the cards or part of the plan. After all, their family home wouldn&#39;t even be licensed for sale. The plan must always have been, from day one, let&#39;s be the most generous and welcoming hosts to this random family who buy a little wine from us sometimes and manage to screw up their credit card details more often than not. With no commercial benefit to be had, and without any real limit or restraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting it plainly, Astrolabe had simply been incredibly generous to us with no expectation of return.&lt;br /&gt;Ultimately, that generosity was what transformed this customer experience into something so special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moments of generosity resonate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the whole thing many months afterwards, some things still stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astrolabe were generous with their service by spotting my mistake, and that alone resonated with me. Humans feel emotional connection when unexpected moments of caring, respect, generosity materialise. And those moments engender two things that are key to brand experience - customer loyalty, and positive word of mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to offer, with no expectation, their time and their hospitality, to both Jo and I, while letting our kids roam their property unwatched, sharing their knowledge and experiences, unfettered, uncensored - THAT kind of generosity leaves such a lasting impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only smart, funny and convivial, but also by showing us such generosity, they converted us into lifelong fans. Done a few times (we can&#39;t be the only such recipients, although I&#39;m sure it cannot be common if only for sake of time) across a customer base, for a reasonable outlay of time, a core of fanatic fans are developed and the initial investment of generosity is repaid many times over. Paying it forward. Beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building generosity into the brand experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this experience, I have learned of other such moments of generosity within customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restaurant that takes the interested child into the kitchen to talk to the chef... and then sends out samples for the kid to try for the rest of the sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency that refunds the customer a month after they realised they booked the wrong date and they&#39;ve wasted a large amount of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The counsellor who compiles the notes from all the sessions into a book for the client to take when they travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eBay seller who responds to damage in delivery with a full refund and no return required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key part of making the customer experience exceptional with generosity is that the benefit is freely given, with no expectation of revenue in return, nor implication of quid pro quo. It is unexpected, and uncommon, but in some part far beyond the customer&#39;s expectation. It resonates, it endures in the memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It probably doesn&#39;t even cost that much, compared to marketing spend and customer acquisition costs. But the payout is huge. You impact powerfully on a customer, and if you are lucky, you engender goodwill and positive word of mouth that lasts a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a long-winded story, and thank you reader for making your way this far through it. As you can tell, this unexpected generosity we received in our customer experience at Astrolabe left an enduring impression on me. I&#39;m writing about it many months later!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I may conclude with one thought, it is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us, myself included, are occupied with the provision of customer experience to others. In some part, large or small, the work you do become the experience of your customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How might you deliver, on occasion, unexpected generosity with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give it some thought. Executed well, generosity can be your customer experience superpower.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>